Gaurav Manchanda

#902, Bhawna CGHS, Sector 43
Gurgaon , Haryana , 122002
9999595554
gauravmanchanda16@gmail.com

Summary

Seeking a challenging position to apply my knowledge and skills for the effective software development, sharpening my technological skills and strengthen my technical knowledge to support organization's growth. More than 7 years of work experience in Web Development using PHP and Ruby on Rails.

Education

MMEC

Mullana, Haryana

B Tech

Graduated June 2009

Information Technology

Employment History

Xebia IT Architects April 2016 - Present

Senior Consultant

Dockerization (Current)

Dockerizing and Automating deployments while migrating multiple Rails/Node apps from In House servers to AWS. Using Docker, Docker Compose, CircleCI, Quay, Make etc

Wealth Analytics (3 Months)

Wealth Analytics Website for clients of one of the Major Management Consultancies. Created using Ruby on Rails. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, AngularJS, Passenger, NGINX, RSpec, Jasmine, Capistrano.

ThoughtWorks Technologies

June 2014 - March 2016

Consultant

Online Betting Website (4 Months)

Worked with one of UK's oldest Football Betting companies on their online betting portal. Developed using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL. Technologies & Tools used: Memcached, Resque, Knockout.js, Rspec, Cucumber, Vagrant, Chef, Lodash, Mingle, Go CD, Passenger, NGINX, OpenSUSE Linux.

Airlines iOS App (2 Months)

Worked with one of the Largest American Airlines on their iOS App. Developed mainly in ObjectiveC, Swift & some Hybrid features in Calatrava. Technologies & Tools used: CoffeeScript, Jasmine, Cucumber, XCode, JIRA, Go CD.

Survey App (8 Months)

Worked with one of the World's Leading Management Consultancies on an Internal App like SurveyMonkey. Developed with Ruby on Rails & Oracle. Technologies & Tools used: jQuery, RSpec, Cucumber, Jenkins, JIRA, OpenSUSE Linux, Passenger, Apache2.

Vinayak Solutions Pvt. Ltd

November 2011 - June 2014

Team Lead

Daily Deals Website (2 Years 5 Months)

Worked on one of Nigeria's first & leading Daily Deals website. Mainly developed with Ruby on Rails. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, Delayed Job, Capistrano, Memcached, jQuery, Prototype, RSpec, JIRA, Pivotal Tracker, Basecamp, Crucible, CodeShip, CodeClimate, Ubuntu Linux, NGINX, Unicorn.

eCommerce Website (3 Months)

One of the leading eCommerce Websites, also based out of Nigeria?. Mainly developed with Ruby on Rails & Spree. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, Delayed Job, Capistrano, Memcached, jQuery, RSpec, JIRA, Ubuntu Linux, Crucible, CodeShip, CodeClimate, Sphinx, NGINX, Passenger.?

eNuke Software Pvt. Ltd

Senior Software Engineer

Online Wine Community (6 Months)

Online portal for Wine Enthusiasts based out os the US. Created in PHP & Drupal. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, jQuery, CentOS, Apache2, Smarty.

Online Deals Website (2 Months)

Online Daily Deals Website based out of ?Ireland. Created in PHP & Drupal. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, jQuery, Ubuntu, Apache2.

Learning Management System (2 Months)

Online LMS based out of Australia.? Created in PHP & Claroline LMS. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, jQuery, CentOS, Apache2.

BMA Prints Pvt. Ltd

April 2010 - January 2011

January 2011 - June 2011

Software Developer & Architect

Online T-Shirt Marketplace (9 Months)

eCommerce Website based out of Delhi, India. Users submit the designs, which are then voted upon and top designs are printed. Developed using PHP & Opencart. Tools & Technologies Used: MySQL, jQuery, Apache2, Filezilla, Ubuntu Linux.

Successive Software Pvt. Ltd

Noida, Uttar Pradesh June 2009 - March 2010

Junior Developer

Real Estate Website (4 Months)

Worked on a Real Estate Website based out of Belgium. Used PHP, Javascript and MySQL.

Website Crawlers (5 Months)

Worked on multiple crawlers written in Python. Used BeautifulSoup & MySQL with Python.

Skills

Languages: PHP, Python, Ruby, JavaScript, CSS, HTML.

Web Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Opencart

Others: AJAX, jQuery, Prototype, Coffee Script, Docker

Web Servers: NGINX, Apache

App Servers: Unicorn, Passenger, Thin, Puma Databases: MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB(A little)

Operating Systems: MSDOS, Windows (XP/7/8/10) and Linux (Ubuntu/CentOS/Fedora/Mint/SUSE), Apple Mac OS X

Project Management Tools: BasecampHQ, Pivotal Tracker, JIRA, Mingle, Github Issues.

Application Monitoring Tools: New Relic, ChartBeat, Google Analytics, Clicky.

Code Version Management: SVN, Git. Continous Integration: CircleCI, CodeShip.

Languages

English: Fluent